SHAIKH ABDUL QADIR

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

shaikhabdulqadir.github.io

Experienced Full Stack Developer with 4 years in the industry and high-level proficiency in the following programs: **PHP(Laravel)**, **Javascript, VueJS, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and DevOps(AWS)**. My experience involves building scalable server-side web apps. I am very familiar and experienced with Web Application Architecture and have worked with a good number of successful development teams.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb 2021 - Present

BOTSIFY INC, KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Integrated several different APIs such as Facebook, Goolgle and Instagram to framework.
- Performed troubleshooting of technical issues within production environment.
- Developed back-end components to connect applications with web services.
- Mentored junior developers to coach on industry best practices and techniques, resulting in competent developers and greater client satisfaction.
- Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device and operating system compatibility.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve surfaced problems.
- Delivered user support to clients to train, educate and answer questions.

APPLICATION LAMP ENGINEER

Dec 2019 - Jan 2021

NEXT GENERATION INNOVATIONS, KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Developed back-end components to connect applications with web services. Wrote server-side and client-side code for projects using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript, specifically with Laravel framework.
- Using tech stack of Laravel MVC Framework, Php, MySql, PostgreSQL, Git, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve surfaced problems.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

November 2017 - November 2019

BOTSIFY INC, KARACHI, PAKISTAN

- Backend development and maintenance of websites using PHP and MySQL.
- Planning and conducting cross-browser usability testing against W3C.
- Developing compatible User Interface functionality using VueJS & other libraries.
- Working in a data analyst role and with business intelligence applications
- Documenting features, technical specifications & infrastructure requirements.
- Working with a multi-disciplinary team to convert business needs into technical specifications.
- AWS/DigitalOcean Server management / deployments of products.

EDUCATION

NED UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY

MS, INFORMATION SECURITY

Jan 2019 - May 2021

SUKKUR IBA UNIVERSITY

August 2013 - May 2017

BACHELORS DEGREE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS



















PERSONAL PROJECTS

Functions Code

https://functionscode.com

Laravel] MySQL] Javascript] HTML] Bootstrap

Functions Code is the public community for developers to share functions of different programming languages

Github Editor

https://github-editor.com

 $igl(extsf{VueJS} igr) igl(extsf{Javascript} igr) igl(extsf{Rest APIs} igr) igl(extsf{Semantic UI} igr)$

Github Editor is basically a sublime format code editor for GitHub repositories, use Github Editor to see any GitHub repository code in the editor instead of doing back and forth of web pages.

CodeinCloud

https://codeincloud.com

Laravel (MySQL) Javascript (HTML) Semantic UI) VueJS

CodeinCloud is the comprehensive IDE on the cloud by which you can connect your Live Servers through SSH Connection and and your hosting directories with FTP access and Enjoy the Live Developments with beautifully designed code

APIsHub

https://apishub.com

[Laravel] MySQL] Javascript] HTML] Bootstrap] VueJS

Github Editor is basically a sublime format code editor for GitHub repositories, use Github Editor to see any GitHub repository code in the editor instead of doing back and forth of web pages.

REST Client APIsHub (Chrome Extension)

https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/rest-client-apishub/dabkfpeebkikmgdianbkchblbdibbfhl

VueJS | Javascript

Rest Client APIsHub is a Chrome Extension for testing APIs

REST Client APIsHub (Firefox Extension)

https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/rest-client-apishub/

VueJS Javascript

Rest Client APIsHub is a Firefox Extension for testing APIs